RACHEL TAIMA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CENTRAL VALLEY OF CA

Mobile: (209) 688-6285 Email: rayuchtai@gmail.com Github: github.com/rayuchtai

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/racheltaima

WHO AM I?

I am a curious pacific islander from California who is compassionate and full of passion. Taking my experience as a writer and an educator, I plan on using my unique skills in formatting a plan that will allow my creative skills to shine through my code as well as be efficient. I desire to connect the evolving world with the islander community that holds their traditions to their hearts.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- NodeJS
- Express
- Mongoose
- MongoDB
- Mongo
- React
- Django
- Python
- Git
- Bootstrap
- Trello

PROJECTS

All the Feels - Mood Booster

Built with React, Javascript, Django, & Python

- Used Axios to make requests to an external api built with Django, deployed on Heroku, to store and track created Moods as well as the comments of a chosen Mood.
- Project was organized with Trello

Pen Pursue - Story Writing Organizer

Built with NodeJS, Mongoose, Express, & EJS

- Following the MVC file structure
- Models for chapters, characters, notes, plots, and settings to allow the user input
- Uses MongoDB Atlas to hold and track the collections

R.W.Reading - Tarot Card Reading

Built with HTML, CSS, Javascript, & JQuery

- Used AJAX to make a request to an external API and inserted some of the data retrieved into the DOM
- Complex user interface modules: modals

EMPLOYMENT

Team Leader

The Table Community | Aug 2019 - Present

- Communicating with students and parents routinely
- Encouraging and caring for the students
- Creating schedules
- Redirecting members of the group to stay on task
- Resolve internal issues as peacefully and efficiently as possible

Team Leader

Jacoby Center | Jan 2019 - May 2019

- Coordinated with other team leaders to lead and engage with our group
- Adapted to unexpected changes in the schedule
- Clearly communicate expectations before every activity
- Respect other team leaders as well as the members of the group
- Delegating tasks within the group to keep things moving efficiently

EDUCATION

General Assembly - Certificate

March 2021 - June 2021

Software Engineering Immersive Remote

San Joaquin Delta College - Associates

August 2012 - May 2020

Interdisciplinary Studies: Arts & Humanities